KESHAV SINGH

MERN Developer

J6386354198 **≥**1816514912@kit.ac.in



Profile Summary

Quick to grasp new concepts and ideas and develop innovative and creative solutions to problems, I am a React. Js developer & have 3 years of experience.

Technical Skills

Programming Languages: HTML/CSS/JavaScript

Databases: MongoDB, Mongoose

Developer Tools: VS Code

Libraries/Frameworks: React.js, Node.js, Express, Redux, Bootstrap, SASS, REST-API, GitHub,

Additional Skills(Basic): DSA,OOPS

Experience

Hcl Technologies

June2022-September2024

Software Engineer Lucknow, U.P.

- Developed and maintained web application susing React.js with redux on the frontend and Node.js with Express.js on the back end.
- Implemented RESTful APIs to connect front-end interfaces with back-end services.
- Conducted API testing using Postman to validate endpoints and ensure data integrity and security.
- Participated in regular meetings to resolve client issues and offered technical support to clients and internal teams.

ClickValley OPC PVT LTD

July2021-June2022

FullStack Engineer

Gurgaon, Haryana

- Collaborated with UX/UI designers and backend developers to ensure seamless integration of frontend components and backend services.
- Used Git and GitHub for version control and collaborated with team members using Git workflows.
- Focus on responsiveness for mobile and desktop and data binding using backend.

Lakshya It Solutions

January2021-June2021

MERN Stack Intern Kanpur, U.P

- Learned Fullstack web development, Html, Css, Bootstrap, Javascript, Reactjs, Nodejs, MongoDB.
- Created Projects with team and particular also.

Projects

SupplyPost/React.js,Redux,Node.js,Express.js,Mongoose,Passport.js

- That was the supply-chain project, I have done all work some from front-end and all back-end part, have completed all data binding.
- I have also worked on responsiveness on that for mobile, Desktop.

PlacementCell/GitHub/Node.js,Express.js,EJS,Passport.js,Mongoose

- Developed a robust placement system to manage the student's placement details providing essential functionalities such users and company registration, update, deletion and search.
- Integrated with functionalities such as scheduling interviews and providing the results of each interviews.
- Integrated MongoDB to store and manage user data and session details efficiently.

Education

A K T University (Percentage: 83.00)

2018-2020

Master of Computer Application

Kanpur, U.P 2015-2018

CSJM University (Percentage: 62.00)

Bachelor of Computer Application

Kanpur, U.P

Achievement

Silver Medal In Hcl

June2023-November2023